back. And today in Kafka stream, I'll
cover what is KStream, KTable, global
KTable. So, generally we have already
covered architecture.
Very, very important. And we have also
done the setup, Kafka stream setup. So,
now at this point of time, we already
know that the very important part of
Kafka stream is topology.
And topology has generally three parts,
source, processor, sink.
So, today I will cover the source part.
Okay?
So, now
we all know that from the architecture
video, source is the entry point of
Kafka stream topology.
It read record from one or more Kafka
topic and forward them to stream
processing pipeline. We have already
seen that that source is the one which
read
the event from the topics, one or more
topics. Okay?
So, there are three ways to read from
the topic. So, that you can say that
the source can be of three type. The
KStream,
KTable, and global KTable. These two are
very important because in interview also
and when you work also, very frequently
asked like difference between KStream
and KTable. Because both are can be used
as a part of source to fetch the data
from the topic. But
there is a difference. Okay?
But yes, global KTable is also
frequently used when you work in the
production.
So, let's see that.
So, first is KStream.
Each record read from source topic
partition is treated as an independent
event. This is very important in the
sense that let's say
I have
three events in my topic. Kafka cluster
we have a topic, right? And let's say
that a particular partition has these
three
events.
Now, here if you see these three events
are all belongs to same order.
001 order ID 001 001, but the status is
changed. Created, shipped, and
delivered.
So, that's where I have written here.
Notice that all three events belongs to
one order ID 001.
Now, the S part of KStream source,
KStream do not maintain any knowledge of
the event, okay, which it previous
previously processed. So, each event is
kind of a new event. So,
KStream sees the them as three separate
events and forward each event to the
stream pipeline.
See,
in very simple word, for the KStream,
even though they are all part of one
order ID only,
it do not care. KStream
considered each event as a separate
independent event.
Okay?
So,
use KStream when each record matter.
Okay? And very important thing is
KStream do not maintain any knowledge
that, "Okay, first time you got created,
and second time I got shipped." So, it
knows that, "Okay, yeah, 001 I have
already got it before." No, it do not
knows that information. Because
here each record matters, and it treat
each record as an independent event.
It do not have any history maintained.
So, see this example, how you can write
it.
So, we have a configuration class, let's
say source types topology. You can give
any name, okay? Now, we are writing one
bean, okay? Now, here if you see,
a stream builder. This stream builder
helps to create topology.
Okay? And generally, we don't have to
create an object of it.
The framework automatically inject it
our bean method. Okay? So, if you
remember when we write in our
application at the rate enable Kafka
stream, in the setup video I have shown
shown that part. At the rate enable
Kafka stream. So, when we have added
into our application
the framework automatically inject the
bean of a stream builder through which
we can create a topology.
Okay? So, now we have I have written one
bean.
You can give any name, KS stream demo.
Stream builder. So,
framework automatically inject the bean
here in this method.
Now, this is how we can write
a
or you can we can create a KS stream.
So, using this object builder
.stream
the topic name
\comma}
and now
the serializer and deserializer what we
wanted, the key and value. So, key I
want to treat it as a string. Value also
treated as a string. You know that
in Kafka topic everything is stored as
bytes.
But, when you are reading it in Java,
you want to convert this bytes to
certain Java object. Okay? So, how you
want to interpret this bytes? So, we
have to tell.
So, keys
treated as a string.
Value treated as a string. In the next
part, I will show you a dedicated video
on this serializer deserializer because
it should be clear properly. But, at
this point of time
everything we have to focus on that what
is KS stream? So, KS stream is like
I am writing builder.stream, the topic
from which you want to read
and the key serializer and so we are
reading, right? So, at the time of
reading we need deserialization. Okay?
So,
SCRDS SerDes, you can say that it is a
combination of both. It's an object
which has both serializer and
deserializer.
Okay? So,
here it will internally make use of
deserialization during consume with. It
make use of deserialization.
So, key deserializer and value
deserializer.
So, this ultimately we get a KStream
object.
Now,
.stream method is used to create
KStream.
Parameter it takes is source topic. I
told you that we can read from more than
one topic, so you can do like this
builder.stream
and list of
event topic one, topic two, you can have
more topic.
And
consume with like your key deserializer
and the value deserializer.
Don't worry about this S E R D S Serdes,
right?
Uh I will cover it in the next part in
totally in depth. But, at this point of
time you will just need to know that in
Kafka we stored as a byte, but when
you're consuming it, you are reading it,
you need to know how to interpret the
key, how to interpret the value.
So,
treat it
is key as a string, treat value as a
string.
Okay?
And this rest part,
don't worry about this because these are
processor and the sync part which we
haven't seen at today, we are focusing
on the source.
Okay? So, how we need to read how to
read from the source topic. So, this is
the part of it.
builder.stream
the topic from which you want to read
and the serializer deserializer.
Okay?
So, we can check that. So, here I have
already started the
my producer, my producer is already
running. And you can see that here, let
me zoom it a bit.
Currently,
the topics which are present is only
countries and order hyphen events. Only
two topics currently present. No data. I
just started as a fresh.
Now,
here in the stream demo,
let me see if I have a proper zoom 150.
So, I think it should be properly
visible.
So, this is the case stream example. So,
let me uncomment it out this bean. The
rest all are commented, right? Yeah.
The same thing.
So, here if you see,
builder dot stream order hyphen events
consume with uh your
deserializer. I provided key
deserializer and the value deserializer.
I want to treat it as a string.
This is just a processor. I don't want
to focus on processor and the sink I as
of today because I don't want to
complicate the things. But here, just
understand that
whatever the event will come
in the processor, I'm just printing it.
Peak.
So, I'm just printing it out the key and
the value.
And in the sink, I am
putting or publishing into this topic
order hyphen events hyphen output.
And produced with because
now we have, let's say, a string object.
We have ultimately, when we have to
publish into the Kafka, we have to put
it into a bytes form. So, produced with
So, I just need to tell that the key
currently is in a string form.
Value is in a string form.
And when it produce, it will convert it
to bytes and put it into the topic.
So, now let me start the
stream application also. So, there is
certain error.
Must not be declared void. Change the
method return type to its annotation.
Okay, let's see that. What's that?
Return
orders.
And here
Let's start it now.
Cool. Application is started. See, don't
worry about this.
All we have to focus first on source.
Once we understand the KStream, KTable,
global KTable, when we come to the
processor, right? With the processor, I
will also cover sync part itself. Then
we have the complete picture.
So, at this point of time, don't worry
about this like what is happening in the
processor, what is happening in the
sync. Uh why return is mandatory? At
this point of time, all we have to
understand what are the different ways
to read from the topic.
So, now our
stream demo application is started. Now,
let me publish one event.
So, order one, customer one product ID
one, let's say quantity 600.
Something I'm let's say publishing.
Order created event published.
So, this is my producer.
Order event sent successfully.
My stream demo, here if you see, I got
this.
Event is consumed. So, it printed this.
Now, here if you see, if I do again list
Now, here if you see
this topic has been
added.
So, this is nothing but our
sync. We are publishing the output into
this topic.
So, in simple term, KStream is clear.
Each event is you can say that
uh evaluated independently.
Okay?
Now, another is KTable. The very
important part is that it is very
similar to KStream,
but
it also maintains the state. Now, how
it's does that?
KTable represent latest state of each
key.
Latest state of each key.
It stores the topic in RocksDB
and continuously update the value
associated with each key.
Understand with an example. Let in this
example, the same the previous one.
Uh I have
three events all with the same order ID
001 001 001.
Now, what would happen when we use
KTable? When we use KTable,
again very similar to KStream only, it
read the event one by one.
So, we have source.
When source process forward this to
processor,
you can say that notes. There can be
like a pipeline complete of the
processor node. Filter, then you might
be doing some map. Like there multiple
steps we can add. And after that, there
could be a sink.
So,
very similar to KStream, it will read
one event,
pass it to the processor node. Processor
node pass it to the sink.
Second time it got second event it got,
it again
pass it to the processor. Processor part
it
uh forward it to sink. Very similar to
KStream. KStream also does that for each
event. But how KTable is different that
at source also,
it maintains you can say that
RocksDB.
RocksDB is nothing but a file in your
local disk. Now, in that one it maintain
the state also that hey, 001
when the record comes, it was status is
created.
The second event come, it also update
this RocksDB. 001 now the status changed
to shipped.
Now the third event come, it also change
the status to 001. Status is now to
delivered.
So, two things. Don't mix it up.
Each event it again process
independently. So, event come created,
source read it, pass it to the
processor, processor will do whatever,
again it put to the sink.
When the event two come, event three
come, it goes to the complete topology
only.
But only thing is during source it also
maintains a RocksDB where it keeps the
latest
continuously update the value associated
with the key. That's the only
distinction you can say that.
So, here the same thing I have
explained.
All three events belongs to one order
ID.
So, what would happen is KTable read
event one by one.
So, read offset zero, 001 created. What
it will do, it update the RockDB.
Earlier it was created.
Forward the event to the stream
pipeline. Second time, it read offset
one, ship. So, it update the RocksDB.
Now it's shipped. And it will forward it
to the stream pipeline.
Third time it read an event, delivered.
So, now it is now delivered.
Update the RockDB, yeah, and forward to
the stream pipeline.
So, this is how it does. So,
very similar.
A stream builder,
this is my another method for KTable
demo. A stream builder.
So, now here if you see, we can use it
like builder.table
your topic name
from where you have to read it.
Consume with your key deserializer and
the value deserializer. Don't worry
about it. I'll tell you in depth, but at
this point of time you need to know that
as part of KTable also we are reading
the event from the topic.
So when we are reading it we have to
convert the bytes to a
certain Java object. So we need to tell
how you want to deserialize it. So we
have to tell for both key and the value.
So currently treated as a string.
Materialized. Why materialized we have
to use?
We whenever the data has to be stored
into the Rocks DB, we generally use
materialized through which we can tell
the name of the store DB file.
Order hyphen event hyphen store is the
name of the Rocks DB file for this one.
And again, in the Rocks DB also
data is stored in bytes form.
I told you if you remember from the
architecture Rocks DB is nothing but a
file, key value file. You can say that
key value file
which has like your key value but is
stored in your local disk. So again, it
is stored the data in the bytes form. So
the key need to be converted, value need
to be converted from your object to the
bytes.
So that's it.
So the key
from a string it will convert to the
bytes, value
bytes ultimately.
So at this point of time all you have to
understand that
with the K table we also maintains a
Rocks DB.
Okay? And whenever you have to read
something from topic, you need to do
deserialization. Whenever you're writing
to a topic, you need serialization. You
have to convert it to a bytes and then
you are able to write it.
Similarly from Rocks DB. Rocks DB also
stored the data in bytes form. So
whenever you have to read it, you have
to deserialize it. Whenever you have to
write it, you have to serialize it
first.
Sorry. That's what we are doing it.
So builder.table,
this is a topic from where we have to
read.
And this serdes, s e r d e s, is nothing
but a object which combine both
serializer and deserializer. Internally,
based on the consume with method, it
make use of deserializer.
So, key would be treated as a string,
value would be treated as a string.
Materialized, now for our RocksDB.
So, as this would be the
file name for our RocksDB.
And with key serdes, with value serdes,
like treated as a string string. Okay,
from a string string it will now convert
to the bytes.
And then it will write to the RocksDB.
Okay?
And here, if you see, this while we are
giving the file name, right?
order-events-store.
You might be thinking, what is this? A
string, \comma} string, \comma} key
value store. So, this first is like
nothing but like uh
your key value. The key is a string,
value is a string.
Okay, that that's why we are using the
key
uh serializer deserializer as a string,
value serializer deserializer as a
string.
So, treat
key as a string, value as a string.
And RocksDB has not only one flavor like
key value, it has multiple flavor.
Another flavor is like window,
which I will cover as a separate part.
Like when we have uh questions like in
last 5 minutes, find out the total
number of orders. Last 10 minutes, what
is the total number of orders? That's
where this window feature comes into the
picture.
So,
that's why I have specifically mentioned
here key value store we want to use. The
this RocksDB
is key value store. There is another
called like window store.
Okay? But for now, we are not using
that, we are just simply using as a key
value store.
So, this is clear. Very simple.
Very similar to KStream, but only thing
is, apart from reading from the topic,
we are also storing it into the
RocksDB file.
That's all.
And this is nothing but the same. Our
processor,
we are picking it, we are writing it.
Print system.out.println.
And the two
is nothing but we are dumping into this
topic.
Okay? So, let's
see it.
So, now here let me
comment out the Kstream.
This is the Ktable demo.
The same code I have shown here.
Okay? Now let me stop the Kstream demo
application.
And start it again.
The same I think issue will come. Let me
have it here.
Return orders.
Let's start the application.
So, application started. Let me publish
an event.
I published an event.
So, let's see K producer application.
Event is
sent successfully.
Now in the Kstream demo application,
here
just a sec.
See.
I'm just checking the topics, right? So,
now here if you see order analytics.
What is this? This is our stream
demo application, right?
Order hyphen analytics. This is our
application name.
Order hyphen events hyphen store. This
is the name which we have given for our
RocksDB file.
Okay? And hyphen change log.
I told you from the if you remember from
the architecture view, architecture
topic,
that
for each RocksDB file a change log topic
is created into our you can say that
Kafka cluster.
Okay, so you know that RocksDB file has
been created and we can also double
check it.
Kafka stream
order analytics
Now here if you see
RocksDB order hyphen events hyphen
store.
Okay?
So RocksDB file has been created with
the name which we have
mentioned and
for this change log topic is also
created in our Kafka cluster.
So means it's working fine the expected
way.
Now couple of doubts might have come.
The one thing is you might be asking hey
what's the point of storing the event
latest state in RocksDB?
When the KTable also send each event
forward to the stream pipeline like
KStream. So in KStream let's say we have
event one event two event three all
belongs to same order order one order
two order one order one order one all
belongs to same order ID.
So in the KTable also we read the event
one by one. So when
event one comes it passes through the
complete topology like KStream.
And only difference is it maintain into
the RocksDB that hey order one current
status is certain S1.
So when event two comes it again passes
to the same topology like KStream but
only thing is it updates the
RocksDB that for order one now status
has changed let's say S2.
So now the question is like what's the
point for each event we are running the
complete topology like KStream what's
the point of maintaining this
information?
See there are two major advantages of
maintaining this RocksDB.
The first,
when some other operation in the stream
pipeline need to look up.
What are those operations? Let's say.
Let's say understand this without
KTable. You are not to using KTable. So,
order topic, customer topic. You are you
have to read two
topics. Your source is two. Your source
is two topics.
Order and customer topic.
So, at time T1,
customer records arrive.
SJ value is Delhi, let's say.
At time T2,
customer record arrives. SJ value is
Bangalore.
See, the same customer SJ earlier was
Delhi.
And another event, same customer SJ,
another is like Bangalore.
It arrives. Because it is a stream,
right? So, it does not maintain any
history. The event comes and it process
through the topology and ultimately it
goes to the sink.
Now, at time T3, order arrives. Order
data comes from here.
SJ
and the
product it purchased, let's say laptop.
Now, one thing you have to do is that
you have to do join with the customer
record that we also know the city of
this user SJ. What's the city? But, will
you be able to know now?
Because earlier we get the record that
hey, SJ Delhi, SJ Bangalore.
But, we are using KStream. KStream do
not maintain any history of the record
which it is processing.
So, it has gone.
So, now, when you want to join with the
customer record, you don't know what
exactly the city of this SJ. So, your
join will not even work. You You have to
populate the city of this SJ. Will you
able to do that? No.
There is nothing to look up.
So, with KTable, it can be helpful. So,
let's say order is our KStream
and the customer is KTable.
So, now at time T1, when customer
records arrive,
okay, so it process it, but it also
maintains a RocksDB. SJ Delhi.
At time T2, when customer records
arrive,
it will process it how it want to
process it, but it also maintains the
RocksDB. Current status SJ is Bangalore
now. Okay, Delhi is updated to
Bangalore.
Now, at time T3, when order arrives,
it will say that, "Okay, I want to join
with the customer record." So, it can
join this RocksDB. Let's say it's
RocksDB is like customer \underscore}
record. This is the file name. So, it
can join with this RocksDB.
Okay, and it find out that, "Hey,
for this SJ, what is the city?" It can
find out that Bangalore.
So, that is one advantage of using
KTable.
Another advantage is interactive
queries. We can expose REST API
endpoints and
when that REST endpoint is exposed,
internally, it can query the RocksDB and
find out the latest updated value of the
key.
We'll see that when we will see go into
more deeper into RocksDB, we'll see
that.
But, that's another advantage. We can
expose REST API endpoint that query this
local state store and return the current
state without querying the external
database.
So, there are certain advantages of
maintaining this RocksDB also.
Now, another doubt you might have come.
Hey Shreyash, the example which we have
taken above, this understand this
example and see
you able to get this doubt or or at this
point of time.
Pause this video here.
Think what all doubts you can get.
Okay? So, this is the doubt I think
this question has come to me. I'm pretty
much sure
uh many of you have also get this
question. So, let's try to find an
answer.
The example which we have taken above
order
KStream
customer KTable.
Does KTable partition event is given
priority over KStream?
Because order event need to do join with
customer data stored in RocksDB.
So, what if order event comes before
customer RocksDB state is created?
So, my doubt is, let's say
now you are reading two source order
and customer.
But this is as KStream, this is
KTable. I'm reading this topic as part
as using KTable
and reading the order topic as
using KStream.
And now I am doing join.
Whenever I get an event from the order,
I join with the customer records.
So, the question is that, hey, first
priority is given to KTable, right?
Okay, read all the events of the
customer, maintain a proper RocksDB, so
that when the order event comes, you
have the data to join.
See,
it is not like that.
So, when you do a fresh start okay, or
let's say application is already
running.
Events comes in parallel. Events arrives
in parallel.
Process record by record in the order
they arrive.
It's not like give priority to the
customer because it's using KTable, give
priority to the KStream because give
priority to the order because it's using
KStream. No.
It's run in parallel
and
order by order. Let's say first this,
then this, then this, then this. Okay?
So, no priority is given to anyone.
No priority given to KTable or KStream.
If an order arrive before its customer,
then join gets null. It won't get any
data. That's how it is.
Yeah, only in case of rebalancing, that
is a exceptional case that when let's
say your application itself goes down
and
earlier you were reading let's say
partition zero
of order topic.
Now it has been assigned to some other
topic
or some other application.
Now you know that it will first create
its Rocks DB internal. From where? From
changelog.
That's I already showed you in the
architecture part.
Okay? So, it will recreate this Rocks DB
from the changelog.
That is something different. That is
restoration or rebalance. Where first
Rocks Rocks DB is let's say get updated
from the changelog. But it doesn't mean
that the priority is given to KTable or
KStream.
Okay?
You got it? So, no priority is given to
anyone. Data arrives in parallel.
If order arrives before and customer
data hasn't come, it get null.
Another doubt.
The join scenario which we have taken in
above example.
So, my order topic I have taken KStream.
Customer topic I have taken KTable.
Now suppose that
the our use case is for each order even
we need to join with customer.
Okay? Let's say SJ laptop.
And our KTable has maintained a Rocks DB
which has let's say SJ belongs to Delhi,
some RJ belongs to Bangalore, Some KJ J
belongs to
like some other city, Jaipur.
Okay?
Now, for whenever any order event comes,
it need to find out that okay, for this
SJ, what is the city?
And it will update this order event with
the
city. That's what we have to do.
Now, the doubt is
because say customer topic has two
partition.
Okay? Let's say we have two threads.
You know that from the architecture
video, each thread maintains their own
RocksDB file.
Okay? Each maintain Each thread holds a
task and each task maintain their own
RocksDB
file.
Okay?
Now, let's say customer has two
partition. This customer
data has two partition.
Now, partition P0 goes in the task one.
And the partition P1 goes to the task
two. So, now let's say this is the use
case.
In my thread one,
okay, let's say this is my application
in which I have put thread equals to
two, two threads. So, all the task will
get divided into these two threads.
So, thread one, thread two. Now, let's
say two task.
Task one is taking care of order
partition zero,
customer partition zero.
Task two is taking care of order
partition one,
and customer partition one. Very
important part is here if you see, the
customer data is divided
into two partition because it has two
partition, and those two partition are
in two different threads. So, they will
both maintain their own RocksDB
file. Because they are using KTable,
right? So, it will maintain their
RocksDB file.
So, it is possible that
here you have got a in the order, you
got a record of SJ, \comma} laptop.
But, the K table
of the customer
which has this information is this task
two. In the partition one, I have
earlier SJ.
Let's say Bangalore.
So,
you can only do join with your local
RocksDB file, right? Will you be able to
do that? No.
Because order comes here in the task one
that hey,
order key is SJ. Now, I want to know
that its city, but its city is present
into customer partition one, which is
hold in a RocksDB file of
task two.
Okay, and two different tasks cannot
access their RocksDB file.
Okay?
So,
this is a very possible scenario which
can happen. And generally, you can say
that uh
the K stream and K table
work seamlessly only when we have
co-partitioning.
So, what does co-partitioning means?
Co-partitioning mean the number of
partition in both order topic and
consumer topics are same.
Okay? So, order has
two partitions, P0, P1.
The consumer
topic also have two partitions, P0 and
P1. First thing.
The second thing is the
key should be same. So, here in the
order, the key is let's say
consumer ID. SJ, let's say.
So, here also, while distributing the
event, the key
of the event should be same, SJ.
So that they always the let's say any
event with key SJ goes to the partition
zero.
Similarly here, the key with the SJ will
go to the partition P0 of a consumer
only.
In that scenario,
this issue will not come.
That's called It's called
co-partitioning. Number of partition in
both order topic and consumer topic are
same and the partition strategy like key
is same for both order and consumer.
Like same key they need to use.
So, that's what I have explained now.
So, now what With this, what would
happen is
So,
let's say
in the partition P0, I have got this
SJ-laptop.
Okay, SJ-phone. These events are going
on.
So, in whichever topic whichever
partition this will go for the order,
let's say P0 it goes.
Now, for the consumer, let's say
the key is same.
The key is same. Whatever the key is
here, let's say SJ, here also key is
let's say SJ.
Okay. So, for the consumer also, it will
go into P0 only.
Okay. So, that whenever any event SJ
\comma} laptop, so where it try to do a
join with the customer data,
so this SJ customer data would also be
present into P0 only.
That's called co-partitioning. Same
number of partition both the topics,
same number of you can say that
partition strategy.
Then only you can say that the KStream
KTable joining is possible.
Otherwise, a problem will come and that
will get resolved through global KTable.
I will tell you now.
But that is clear?
KStream KTable is clear?
Okay.
Now, understand this global K-table.
Global K-table is like
I have told you the problem you got the
problem with the K-table, right? The
same thing I have explained here. But
now let's take instead of consumer take
countries example.
Imagine in Kafka stream application we
have two stream thread
and we have order topic with two
partition, countries topic with two
partition. Same thing. So you have two
threads.
Okay? So one thread has task one,
another thread is another task.
And this task is taking care of order
partition P0, this task is taking care
of order partition P1.
Similarly
it is taking care of country partition
P0, country partition P1.
The exact same thing which I have told
you that it is possible that
task one, this task one get countries
Okay? It will see some countries. Let's
say here it will maintain its RocksDB it
has let's say country code IN and its
value India.
And here it has maintain its RocksDB, it
has let's say US United
States. It is maintain its own RocksDB
file, country code and the country name.
Now it has to do join. Let's say here in
the order I have got for US.
Will it be able to find into its
RocksDB? No, because US is present into
here.
That's what I told you.
Many times co-partition is not possible.
You can't have the two different topics
following the same partitioning
strategy. It's very difficult.
So this is very likely that here you
want to do join with the table or you
join with the topic, different topic,
but those topics has different
partitioning strategy. So this use case
might come and your join will fail. Like
you got an order
which has a country code US, you wanted
a complete name.
But if you you can only do a join off
with your store, you can get you get no
value here US.
The country code here it is in partition
P1 of the countries here in the task
two.
So, what to do that?
Global KTable comes into the picture.
Now, understand that what happened is
each Kafka stream application
gets all partitions this data of the
global KTable topic. What does it mean?
Let's say that I have a Kafka stream
application.
Okay, the same Spring Boot application
which we have created. This is a Kafka
stream application only. And here we
have defined stream thread equals to
two.
So, here we have two thread, thread one,
thread two.
Okay.
Now,
order is our KStream.
Order is our KStream. Okay, multiple
thread, each thread is
their own task and each task is taking
care of one partition of a order.
Now, what about country?
Countries topic
which has two partition.
P0 and P1.
We know that
this issue.
Okay, the partitioning strategy of order
and the country is not same.
So, we can't use KTable. How to do that?
So, this country topic we will read it
as global
KTable.
Now, what we will do
it will have this application, my this
application.
It will create another thread, global
stream thread. What this will this
thread will do, it will create a RocksDB
file only
and read all the partition of this
topic.
So, for this countries topic you have
written that hey, read this topic.
Now, since it is global K table, it read
all the partition.
Okay?
And also,
this global RocksDB file is accessed by
your all task in different threads
present into same application.
So, you can say that
each Kafka stream application, so each,
very important, each Kafka stream
application. So, this is my application
which has two thread and this two thread
can have multiple task. All can access
this global RocksDB file, which is
maintained as part of global global K
table.
So, if you have another application,
application two, it has its own two
threads. So, it will again read all the
partition of the
global topic, which you have seen. So,
country, I have read it as global
K
table.
So, all P0 P1, both the topics of the
countries would be read and stored into
the RocksDB.
And now,
this application, whatever how many
threads it's running with this thread,
how many tasks tasks are running, they
would be able to read it.
So, that is clear.
All tasks running within this
application instance can query this
shared global state store.
So, very important, always use global K
store for relatively small or reference
database, like countries, country code,
configuration, which are static and
small. Because you are reading all the
topics, all the partition of the topic.
Okay? So, your data set should be small.
And also, each application instance,
your each application instance does
this.
So, your data set should be small. So,
don't use global K table for any any
topic. okay?
And also, very important that
when you start the application,
this is done first. So, you have this
priority number one.
So, first it read P0 P1 of the topic
which you marked as read as a global
KTable. So, it maintain this
global RockDB file first. After that, it
will start your KStream threads and your
task will run.
Okay? So, that's what I mentioned, it's
read first behavior.
Only for global KTable, not for regular
KTable. I've already told you regular
KTable is
no priority over KStream or something.
It read one by one, but only global
KTable is like
it first create this global
first and only after that it will
start your stream thread.
So, okay? So, here if you see how you
can do that, very simple.
The same stream builder,
builder.globalTable.
Now, you can use this method,
globalTable and the topic name which you
want to read.
Again, the topic you have to read, so
you have to provide the deserialization,
so we are using serdes. Uh serdes, your
key and value.
Okay? Deserialize key as a string,
deserialize key a value as a string.
And global table also maintains a
RocksDB file. Okay, very similar to
KTable only, but only thing it's global.
So, you have we can do materialized as
whatever the name of the RocksDB file
you want to give and the key and value.
Because now we are going to insert, so
it's like a serialization. So, key
serialization is a string, value
serialization as a string.
Okay?
So, this is how we can do that. So, here
if you see,
let me uh stop the streams application.
Let's comment out the
KTable also. Now, let's uncomment out
this global KTable.
Okay.
So, let's run this.
Okay. I think it we need to return it.
So,
let's return this one.
Let's KStream enriched.
Okay. So, our application is started.
Now, let's see. Here, if you see
this global has come.
Okay. So, this global has come, RocksDB
countries-store. That's what we did
there.
So, here if you see
what we're storing countries-store.
And very important one more thing is
that if you see this, if I do
hyphen-hyphen list,
there is no like
country-store-changelog.
See.
For this KTable, this is also a
This is also a your RocksDB file.
RocksDB
file. But, this is global.
But, for this
change log is not created.
You can ask like, "Hey, why change log
is not created?"
I told you that whenever you start an
application,
whenever you start an application,
it read all the partition all the
partition and rebuild this
RocksDB file.
So, that is one thing. First, it has to
read all the partition and rebuild it.
Another thing is
it is global KTable is only meant for a
small relatively small data set like
countries, country code configuration
which are generally static. Not change
so frequently.
So, there is no you can say that
from theoretically we are saying that
use global KTable for only small data
set and when it is a small data set and
you have to read all the partition of
that that should be fine. That's why
don't maintain a change log. So, the
original
So, this is my original uh
topic.
So, your countries is the original
topic, right? This is where you are
reading.
So, this countries has related two
partition.
P0 P1 countries.
So, your
RocksDB global
your global
your countries
has two partition P0 P1 and now the your
global
RocksDB
has all the data from this P0 and P1.
All the data from this P0 P1. And there
is no change log.
in Kafka cluster.
So, why we are saying that first of all
this is global? So, whenever any
application start, it first create this.
Means it will read this countries topic
all partition and rebuild this. So, in
the change log happen in the change log
also it will happen the same thing.
It will read even by even all and then
it will rebuild it.
So, it will the same thing.
Because all topics are present. All it
has to read all topics. If it is only
one topic, then it makes sense.
Okay, change log for only let's say this
partition P0. It will have It has to
build only partition P0.
Okay, but since it has to do all
partition, doesn't make sense to create
a change log. This original topic is
something you have to read it again.
Another thing is uh
It is meant for the small data set
itself.
So, it's okay to read the whole
partition P0, partition one, partition
two again.
Okay, all the partition. It's okay to
read it because it contains small data
set.
Clear?
I hope with this part of the Kafka
stream, we are clear with the source
like
when to use KStream, when to use KTable,
when to use global KTable.
In the next part, I will tell you about
this
search, serializer, deserializer.
Okay, guys, any doubt? Let me know in
the comment section. Bye.